Stuart Levy Papers MS244
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Stuart Levy Papers
circa 1975 -- 2017
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Levy, Stuart
MS244
6.8 Linear Feet
This collection contains records documenting Stuart Levy's work from 1975-2017 as a professor at the Tufts University School of Medicine and as the Director of the Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stuart Levy, 2018, accession number MS-2018-066.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series by format, and chronologically where possible.
Related Materials
Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance Records, 1975-2000. Tufts University. Digital Collections and Archives. Medford, MA.
Content Description
This collection contains press binders from 1975 through 2017, which consist of clippings, print outs, and other documentation of Stuart Levy and his work at the Tufts University School of Medicine and as the Director of the Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance; loose photographs and photograph albums created or kept by Levy and his staff; and recorded lectures by, interviews with, or events featuring Levy or his work on VHS, CD, and DVD.
Biographical / Historical
Stuart B. Levy is the Director of the Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance at the Tufts University School of Medicine, as well as a Staff Physician at the Tufts Medical Center.
Levy was born in 1938. He earned his bachelor degree from Williams College, and his medical degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1965. While studying for his medical degree, Levy took time off to pursue additional research opportunities, including researching radiation genetics in Paris, and studying "transferable bacterial resistance to antibiotics" in Tokyo with Tsutomu Watanabe. After medical school, Levy completed his residency at Mount Sinai Hospital in New York, before doing postdoctoral research at the National Institutes in Health.
A fundamental theme of Levy's career has been researching the problem of antibiotic resistance. Over the course of more than four decades at the Tufts University School of Medicine, Levy specialized in hematology. He was a co-founder and president of The Alliance for the Prudent Use of Antibiotics. Levy was also a past President of the American Society for Microbiology, and a cofounder and Chief Scientific Officer of Paratek Pharmecuticals Inc. Additionally, in 1992, Levy founded and directed the Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance, investigating adaption responses of different cells. Levy has published over three hundred papers, and edited four books. He retired from the School of Medicine in 2018.
Faculty papers; Medical history; Medicine -- History; Drug resistance in microorganisms.; Antibiotics--Evaluation.
- Stuart Levy papers, circa 1975 -- 2017; MS244.001; 6.8 Linear Feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is open for research.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by format, and chronologically where possible.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains press binders from 1975 through 2017, which consist of clippings, print outs, and other documentation of Stuart Levy and his work at the Tufts University School of Medicine and as the Director of the Center for Adaptation Genetics and Drug Resistance; loose photographs and photograph albums created or kept by Levy and his staff; and recorded lectures by, interviews with, or events featuring Levy or his work on VHS, CD, and DVD.
  - Press binders, 1975 -- 1999; MS244.001.001; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 1)
  - Press binders, 2000 -- 2004; MS244.001.002; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 2)
  - Press binders, 2005 -- 2012; MS244.001.003; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 3)
  - Press binders and photographs, circa 1975 -- 2017; MS244.001.004; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 4)
    This file contains press binders from 2013 through 2017, other public relations material from 1975 through 2000, and photographs from circa 1995 through 2017.
  - Photograph albums and recorded lectures and interviews, circa 1990 -- 1999; MS244.001.005; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 5)
    This file contains photograph albums and recorded lectures by or interviews with Levy on VHS.
  - Oversize photograph albums, circa 1975 -- 2000; MS244.001.006; .6 Linear Feet (Box 6)
  - Recorded lectures and interviews on CD and DVD, 2005 -- 2011; MS244.001.007; .2 Linear Feet (Box 25, 122, 3, 7, 36)
    This file is open for research, but is minimally processed and may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
    - Royal Society Presentation 2008, MS244-001
    - Cold Spring Harbor May, 2011, MS244-002
    - ICAAC 2010, MS244-003
    - WHO July 2008, MS244-004
    - ASM Biodefense 2009, MS244-005
    - Plasmodium Genome Papers 2002, MS244-006
    - Global Health 2005, MS244-007
    - Gates Presentation 2006, MS244-008
    - World Congress 2006, MS244-009
    - Grand Rounds Lecture 2007, MS244-010
    - ICAAC 2009, MS244-011
    - Alumni Talk 2008, MS244-012
    - MIT Talk 2008, MS244-013
    - ASN General Meeting Toronto 2007, MS244-014
    - NPR National Science Friday 2005, MS244-015
    - Biomerieux 2007, MS244-016
    - Santo Domingo Presentation 2007, MS244-017
    - ASM Antiseptic 2003, MS244-018
    - NIH Viral Presentation 2005, MS244-019